KERU CHEN

Tel.: +86-13901211166

cliverchen.github.io/

PROFILE

I am currently a junior majoring in Automation at Xi'an Jiaotong University. My research interests span the field of artificial intelligence, particularly reinforcement learning and its applications in areas like healthcare and robotics. I possess a strong sense of self-motivation, an aptitude for self-directed learning, and a knack for problem-solving. My fervent passion lies in scientific research.

EDUCATION

Xi'an Jiaotong University University

Bachelor of Engineering in Automation

- University Physics
- Computer graphic
- Reinforcement learning

RELEVANT COURSEWOEK

- Data structures • Programming design
- Operational research
- Machine learning
- Pattern recognition

EXPERIENCE

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Jan 2024 - Present

Sep 2021 - Present

Current GPA: 3.4/4.3

Research intern

- Supervised by **Prof. Tianlong Chen** from Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard, who will soon join The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill as an Assistant Professor of Computer Science.
- Focus on the emergent abilities in multi-modal large language models.
- Conduct relevant experiments and expect to produce conference papers.

University of Houston

Sep 2023 - Present

Research intern

- Supervised by **Prof. Sen Lin** from University of Houston.
- Combine jump start reinforcement learning and constrained reinforcement learning and design and analyze the algorithm theoretically.
- Carry out related experiments and anticipate generating papers.

Chinese Academy of Sciences

Feb 2023 - Oct 2023

Research intern

Xi'an, China

- Supervised by Prof. An Pan from Pioneering Interdiscipline Center, State Key Laboratory of Transient Optics and Photonics, CAS.
- Undertook the task of improving Fourier Ptychography Microscope algorithm and helped the professor complete the experiment.
- Published review article titled Fourier ptychographic microscopy 10 years on: A review on Cells (JCR Q1, IF=7.67).

PROJECTS

Waveformer: A Transformer based EEG Sleep Stage Classifier

Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

- Supervised by **Prof. Gang Wang** from The Biomedical-Information Engineering laboratory of State Ministry of Education, school of Life Science and Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University.
- Combined with deep learning and signal processing techniques, i.e. encoder block of Transformer, convolutional auto-encoder and wavelet transform to classify sleep stages using EEG, and reached a classification accuracy of 75% in a private dataset, the highest level in this course.
- This project and its report have been uploaded to Github.

Information propagation in social networks based on independent cascade model Apr 2023 - Jun 2023

- Supervised by Prof. Zhanbo Xu from Ministry of Education Key Lab For Intelligent Networks and Network Security, school of Automation Science and Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University.
- Designed a more efficient propagation simulation algorithm by combining with Monte Carlo algorithm and heuristic algorithm according to the given network and the number of nodes required to be propagated.
- This project and its report have been uploaded to Github.

- Project description National Training Program of Innovation and Entrepreneurship for Undergraduates.
- Supervised by Prof. Jingang Shi from School of Software Engineering, Xi 'an Jiaotong University.
- Participate in designing and conducting experiments of IDPT algorithm, which published in IJCAI2022.
- Improved IDPT algorithm and build web-demo based on Flask and Ajax according to the algorithm to realize face detection, crop and super-resolution restoration of a given photo.

Four-wheeled robot with mechanical arms based on Mecanum wheel

Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

- Supervised by **Prof. Jun Xu** from State Key Laboratory for Manufacturing System Engineering, school of Mechanical Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University .
- Participated in the design of the robot arm structure, and completed the modeling and simulation with SolidWorks.
- Used MATLAB and Simulink to complete the simulation of the manipulator control and tuned PID control.

HONORS AND AWARDS

Mathematical modeling competition of Xi 'an Jiaotong University Second Prize

Aug 2022

Second National Artificial Intelligence Knowledge Compitition for College Students First Prize

Jun 2022

SKILLS

Language: Mandarin (Native speaker) and English (fluent)

Standard test: IELTS 6.5 test date 01/19/2024

Technical Skills: Python (PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, etc.), C/C++, Matlab, LaTeX, Git/GitHub, Linux, Altium

Designer, SolidWorks

Hobbies: Photography, Cuisine, Basketball